<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
>
  <channel>
    <title>Carbs Linux</title>
    <description>a simple linux distribution</description>
    <link>https://carbslinux.org</link>
    <atom:link href="https://carbslinux.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <lastBuildDate>Thu Sep 10 2020 11:00</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>August 2020 News Post</title>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200803.html</link>
<description>&lt;h1&gt;August 2020 News Post&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are having some stalls during this summer, as I am currently working on
university-related stuff. Nonetheless, there are some important changes that I
want to share in this month&amp;rsquo;s post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;INDEX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#carbs-packaging-tools&quot;&gt;Carbs Packaging Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#docs&quot;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#re-opening-the-carbs-linux-server&quot;&gt;Re-opening the Carbs Linux server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Carbs Packaging Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month I have reworked &lt;code&gt;kiss&lt;/code&gt; into a new package manager, now renamed as
&lt;code&gt;cpt&lt;/code&gt;. Updating &lt;code&gt;kiss&lt;/code&gt; will now bootstrap the new package manager, so you don&amp;rsquo;t
have to manually edit your system. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of this, you can
look up the &lt;code&gt;post-install&lt;/code&gt; script on &lt;code&gt;core/kiss&lt;/code&gt; and apply the changes manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will also need to rename your KISS&lt;em&gt;* variables to CPT&lt;/em&gt;*. So, KISS_PATH
becomes CPT_PATH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rework changes the previous commands on the package manager into standalone
tools, and move the package manager functions to a library. This makes it easier
for a user to import functions and variables from the package manager, and
extend the package manager with their own intended way. Previously this required
ugly hacks and workarounds to use the package manager functions. I will be
making use of these changes to re-implement binary package management functions
as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to use the library on your script you can simply do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;+--------------------------------------------------------------------------+
|                                                                          |
| #!/bin/sh                                                                |
| . cpt-lib                                                                |
| (...)                                                                    |
|                                                                          |
+--------------------------------------------------------------------------+
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are obviously some clean-up and simplifications needed in this new
tool-based package management method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Docs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have added documentation for the distribution, and finally updated the guide
for installation. It is now &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; complete. These docs can be installed to
your system for online viewing. I will also add a documentation crawler similar
to how werc&lt;a href=&quot;http://werc.cat-v.org&quot;&gt;^1&lt;/a&gt; works (but as an offline viewer). You can find &lt;code&gt;carbs-docs&lt;/code&gt; from
the repository. Currently, the documentation lacks but I will be adding new
stuff. These will solely be distribution specific documentation and will not be
a wiki-like source. If anyone would like to contribute to a wiki-like
documentation source, I would happily re-open the distribution wiki. You can
find the source on https://github.com/CarbsLinux/docs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Re-opening the Carbs Linux server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in May, I had shutdown the Carbs Linux server due to financial issues, but
I am slowly reverting to the self-hosted model. Back then, the git repositories
were mirrored to GitHub, and the management was overall much more flexible. The
server used to run Carbs Linux as well (that was fun and horrifying at the same
time). Now, I will be relaunching the git server which will be the upstream
source before August 5. You can switch your remote, but GitHub will stay as a
remote nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: The git-server is up!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>June Newspost</title>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200617.html</link>
<description>&lt;h1&gt;June Newspost&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be an active month for Carbs as major changes to the base and the
package manager will be coming up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Statically linking the base&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past couple of weeks I have been trying to simplify the base and
statically link the core (mostly binaries rather than libraries). I usually see
some people extremely opposed to static linking as I also see the opposite on
people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that binaries on the core should always be linked statically. This
ensures that an SONAME bump to &lt;code&gt;libObscure.so&lt;/code&gt; will not break the core
functionality of your system, forcing you to use external resources to recover
from such an issue. As long as you can compile, use core utilities, edit text,
and access the web, you can solve any given issue on your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that removing shared libraries is sensible either. Not
every piece of software out there is good quality enough to be statically
linked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Major changes on the core repository&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been drastic changes to the core repository and the base rootfs this
month (with more on the way). Right now changes are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Removed from Core&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;libressl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;grub&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bison&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;dhcpcd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ubase&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Added to Core&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bearssl&lt;/code&gt;, as a &lt;code&gt;libressl&lt;/code&gt; replacement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;byacc&lt;/code&gt;, as a &lt;code&gt;bison&lt;/code&gt; replacement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Statically linked&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;kiss&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;neatvi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mandoc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;byacc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;m4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;e2fsprogs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pkgconf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sbase&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;libnl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;wpa_supplicant&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bearssl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Making the wiki available offline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, all documentation regarding Carbs Linux will be avaialable to be installed
from the core repository in a &lt;code&gt;carbs-docs&lt;/code&gt; package along with its own document
crawler. Currently, the documentation regarding the installation process is a
little outdated which will also receive some important updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;ISO image for Carbs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thinking of releasing an ISO image in order to provide a standardized
environment for installation along with installation helper tools in the spirit
of &lt;code&gt;arch-install-scripts&lt;/code&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how that&amp;rsquo;s going to play out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>kiss 2.0.0 and overall changes</title>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200528.html</link>
<description>&lt;h1&gt;kiss 2.0.0 and overall changes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbs Linux kiss version 2.0.0 has been released which introduces
rsync repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Git is no longer a mandatory dependency for the package manager,
every git source on the core repository has been replaced with
https sources (sbase, sinit), and rootfs tarballs will no longer
ship with git. Repositories in the upcoming tarball will be rsync
repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Git is now on the &lt;code&gt;extra&lt;/code&gt; repository and is still (optionally)
used in the package manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this change is size reductions and increased
speed with rsync. As I said on the previous post, git repositories
get larger and larger over the time span. Currently my personal
copy of the git repository is around 77MB and I have forked KISS
Linux (as a shallow copy) around December. Obviously, I have commits
that I ommitted. I tend to create commits I dislike, which I change
with &amp;lsquo;git reset &amp;ndash;soft HEAD^&amp;rsquo;, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually remove the
commits, etc. A user will have a repository much smaller than mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a precaution with the added bonuses of speed and dropping a
mandatory dependency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the rest of the changelog &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/kiss/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Binary Repositories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I have also published &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/kiss-bin&quot;&gt;kiss-bin&lt;/a&gt;, a first version
for managing binary repositories. Currently, there are some caveats
that I&amp;rsquo;ll be fixing along the way. I decided not to include this
in the package manager natively as managing the source based and
binary based packages together adds levels of complexity that we
do not want. Instead, this is an extension for kiss which sources
the package manager as a library. I hope to see it being adopted
by others interested on the matter as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
Cem&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Relation of Carbs and KISS</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200508.html</link>
<description>&lt;h1&gt;The Relation of Carbs and KISS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; May 08 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I have forked KISS, I have received many questions
that can be summarized as &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo;. I have realized that I
never truly answered this question. That&amp;rsquo;s the reason I am
writing this post, to give some background on Carbs, and
some differences between KISS Linux and Carbs Linux for
anyone who may be wondering. Perhaps I could make this a
&amp;ldquo;FAQ&amp;rdquo; page later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the idea of creating my own Linux distribution since
the May of 2019. Back then, I had my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxfromscratch.org&quot;&gt;Linux from Scratch&lt;/a&gt;
build, and I wanted to slim it down my own way and replace
the software (with musl,sbase,etc.). The name Carbs Linux
was in my mind since then. I wanted to write my own package
manager, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t satisfied with anything I had built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had written some incomplete package managers (all named &lt;code&gt;fat&lt;/code&gt;)
and I quickly threw them into the trash can, where they
honestly belonged. I would want to share them with you for
laughs, but my hard-drive got wiped and I have a problem
of not doing an &amp;ldquo;initial commit&amp;rdquo; until a program I write
is in a usable state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have obtained the &amp;lsquo;carbslinux.org&amp;rsquo; domain name in September
2019, but then life got on the way, and I stopped for a long
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day on Reddit, I saw Dylan&amp;rsquo;s post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/unixporn&quot;&gt;r/unixporn&lt;/a&gt; about
KISS, and I really thought that it was interesting. Here is
my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/unixporn/comments/ducd34/sowm_kiss_d/f7lua7x&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; to Dylan on that post. I checked out the package
manager and the repository. The packaging system was extremely
clean and well-thought. I decided to give it a go and fork
KISS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Differences between KISS and Carbs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I still baffle when people ask me this question. My
intention was never to create a distribution with specific
differences between KISS. My intention was being my own
BDFL of a distribution I maintain. There are lots of
differences between the main repositories, but they are subtle
and not worth talking about. I personally never even installed
KISS Linux on my system. So Carbs, isn&amp;rsquo;t something like a
downstream fork of KISS, it is just a distribution that was
initially based on KISS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to contribute as much as I can to KISS Linux. I think
that it is a brilliant distribution, and it was a great starting
point for Carbs. I am really grateful to Dylan and all the
other contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m working on now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I have a few projects that I&amp;rsquo;m working on for Carbs.
These are,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A BSD port for Carbs. For a while, I have been working on BSD
compatibility on my fork of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carbslinux/kiss&quot;&gt;package manager&lt;/a&gt;. I have tested,
without any more issues, on OpenBSD and FreeBSD. The biggest
issues remaining are choosing a vendor for BSD, packaging the
BSD source, and providing a minimal base (like busybox for BSD).
If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with BSD, it has a single source code
for all of the utilities (kernel, command line programs, etc.).
Contributions (even chipping in ideas) are very welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding binary package distribution support natively to the package
manager. Biggest issue in small/old computers are compile times.
This feature is for the bigger packages such as webkit, clang,
llvm that take a considerable amount of time. Some computers
with low memories cannot even compile firefox/webkit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding rsync repository support to the package manager. This
is not a current issue, but rather a futureproofing. As time
passes, distribution repositories grow larger. KISS and Carbs
are young distributions without this problem right now. But
in something like 5 years, this size will presumably increase
to hundreds of megabytes. At that point it will be pointless
to have the repository sources unless you specifically need them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s up with all the init/service daemons?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ever checked the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carbslinux/repository&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;, you may have noticed
that there are lots of init/service related packages. I have had
my fair share of time with all of them, and it is an area that I
am really interested in. I have even written my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cemkeylan/shinit&quot;&gt;init daemon&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cemkeylan/sysmgr&quot;&gt;service supervisor&lt;/a&gt;. I maintain all those packages on KISS
Community Repository as well with the exception of busybox. Those
are, &lt;code&gt;busybox init/runit&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;runit&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;sinit&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;sysmgr&lt;/code&gt;. I would
definitely recommend checking out &lt;code&gt;shinit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sysmgr&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why I don&amp;rsquo;t publicize Carbs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of reasons I don&amp;rsquo;t publicize Carbs a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KISS is the better alternative in terms of support and community.
I work on maintaining this distribution just as hard as Dylan,
but in the end, Carbs is based on his original hard work, and I
believe that he deserves the recognition more than I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I cannot answer questions like &amp;ldquo;What is the difference?&amp;rdquo;, I
prefer staying as the silent sibling project of KISS Linux. Plus,
there is no point in dividing the newly-emerging community in half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not because I don&amp;rsquo;t have ideas for the future of Carbs, I
do. I just think that I will deserve the recognition once those
above lists are checked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that&amp;rsquo;s about it, if you have questions you can send me a
mail, ping me on IRC (my handle is &lt;code&gt;merakor&lt;/code&gt;), and I will be happy
to answer. Maybe your question fits this post, and I can update it
to thoroughly give an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
Cem&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Outsource Repository Concept</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200410.html</link>
<description>&lt;h1&gt;Outsource Repository Concept&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 3rd, I have added submodule support for Carbs
Linux&amp;rsquo;s fork of &lt;code&gt;kiss&lt;/code&gt;. Now, from that sentence, it really
doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound exciting at all. But in reality, it opens a
path to lots of creative output, and a better way to manage
multi-user repositories (such as KISS Community).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When managing a repository of submodules, the repository
maintainer&amp;rsquo;s only job is to deal with adding packages.
A package maintainer doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for the repository
maintainer to update their packages, as they are only making
the changes to their own repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, an end-user can also track from their preferred
maintainers, and do that with the tidyness of a single repository
in their &lt;code&gt;KISS_PATH&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbs Linux now has an outsource repository for some packages.
Firefox and its dependencies have been purged from the main repository,
but can be found on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/outsource&quot;&gt;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/outsource&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Roadmap for Carbs</title>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200406.html</link>
<description>&lt;h1&gt;Roadmap for Carbs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a busy week. There are lots of changes in
direction, and more to come. I want to talk a little
about all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Carbs Linux Server Going Down&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became harder to maintain and pay for the server, and I will be
shutting it down in May. I am currently in the phase of
carrying over everything to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. The repository and the
website is served on Github now. I have also moved the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/wiki/wiki&quot;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;
to Github and anyone can edit it there. There are some outdated
posts that I will be fixing around this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not quite sure where to store the downloads page now. But I
will be switching that to a new source as well. (Maybe Source Forge?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel a little sad for switching, but serving on Github is faster,
cheaper, and hassle-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Forking KISS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a personal fork of KISS, which I enjoyed thoroughly. I didn&amp;rsquo;t
intend to make it the default when I started it, but it has matured
enough to be so. The package manager can now be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/kiss&quot;&gt;this repository&lt;/a&gt;.
See it for the added changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a change for the better, as I can develop the package
manager as it fits my views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Small Changes on the Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made some small changes on the website. The build is not dependent
on Plan9 utilities anymore. It was fun messing around with &lt;code&gt;rc&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;mk&lt;/code&gt;,
but they are quite limited compared to POSIX shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSS feeds are finally working as intended, both for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://carbslinux.org/news.xml&quot;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt; section, and
the &lt;a href=&quot;https://carbslinux.org/rss.xml&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; secion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see every page&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;.txt&lt;/code&gt; output at the end of the page by clicking
&amp;lsquo;View Page Source&amp;rsquo;. Meanwhile, I will be updating some pages to be a little
more &amp;lsquo;human-readable&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Outsources Repository&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have opened an &lt;code&gt;outsource&lt;/code&gt; repository, which I will be pushing this week.
I will add a new post when I am ready to push it. I think it will be interesting,
it will also make more sense about the changes I have added to the package
manager. The now empty repository, can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/outsource&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New Tarball&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have released a new tarball today, which can be obtained from the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.carbslinux.org/releases&quot;&gt;downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning to add more of these update posts as I&amp;rsquo;m feeling better about
the website structure overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Cem&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Switching to New Website</title>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200128.html</link>
<description>&lt;h1&gt;Switching to New Website&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 28 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it before, this website
was powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://werc.cat-v.org&quot;&gt;werc&lt;/a&gt;. And
even though I liked it really much, it was too
powerful for a small website like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have decided to reimplement this website with
my own static generation scripts. The source will
probably be on &lt;a href=&quot;https://carbslinux.org/git/website/log.html&quot;&gt;https://carbslinux.org/git/website/log.html&lt;/a&gt;
when I decide to publish the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The generation requires Plan9 programs, although
I have used them just for my enthusiasm. I have built
the site with a combination of mk (instead of make), rc,
and POSIX sh. I am not yet exactly familiar with rc,
but I will replace the shell scripts when I feel like
I can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
  </channel>
</rss>
