<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
>
<channel>
<title>Carbs Linux</title>
<description>a simple busybox linux distribution</description>		
<link>https://carbslinux.org</link>
<atom:link href="https://carbslinux.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<lastBuildDate>Apr Sun 2020 21:00</lastBuildDate>
<item>
<title>Outsource Repository Concept</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200410.html</link>
<description>&lt;h1&gt;Outsource Repository Concept&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 3rd, I have added submodule support for Carbs
Linux&amp;rsquo;s fork of &lt;code&gt;kiss&lt;/code&gt;. Now, from that sentence, it really
doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound exciting at all. But in reality, it opens a
path to lots of creative output, and a better way to manage
multi-user repositories (such as KISS Community).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When managing a repository of submodules, the repository
maintainer&amp;rsquo;s only job is to deal with adding packages.
A package maintainer doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for the repository
maintainer to update their packages, as they are only making
the changes to their own repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, an end-user can also track from their preferred
maintainers, and do that with the tidyness of a single repository
in their &lt;code&gt;KISS_PATH&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbs Linux now has an outsource repository for some packages.
Firefox and its dependencies have been purged from the main repository,
but can be found on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/outsource&quot;&gt;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/outsource&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Roadmap for Carbs</title>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200406.html</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a busy week. There are lots of changes in
direction, and more to come. I want to talk a little
about all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Carbs Linux Server Going Down&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became harder to maintain and pay for the server, and I will be
shutting it down in May. I am currently in the phase of
carrying over everything to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. The repository and the
website is served on Github now. I have also moved the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/wiki/wiki&quot;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;
to Github and anyone can edit it there. There are some outdated
posts that I will be fixing around this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not quite sure where to store the downloads page now. But I
will be switching that to a new source as well. (Maybe Source Forge?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel a little sad for switching, but serving on Github is faster,
cheaper, and hassle-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Forking KISS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a personal fork of KISS, which I enjoyed thoroughly. I didn&amp;rsquo;t
intend to make it the default when I started it, but it has matured
enough to be so. The package manager can now be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/kiss&quot;&gt;this repository&lt;/a&gt;.
See it for the added changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a change for the better, as I can develop the package
manager as it fits my views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Small Changes on the Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made some small changes on the website. The build is not dependent
on Plan9 utilities anymore. It was fun messing around with &lt;code&gt;rc&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;mk&lt;/code&gt;,
but they are quite limited compared to POSIX shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSS feeds are finally working as intended, both for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://carbslinux.org/news.xml&quot;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt; section, and
the &lt;a href=&quot;https://carbslinux.org/rss.xml&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; secion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see every page&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;.txt&lt;/code&gt; output at the end of the page by clicking
&amp;lsquo;View Page Source&amp;rsquo;. Meanwhile, I will be updating some pages to be a little
more &amp;lsquo;human-readable&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Outsources Repository&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have opened an &lt;code&gt;outsource&lt;/code&gt; repository, which I will be pushing this week.
I will add a new post when I am ready to push it. I think it will be interesting,
it will also make more sense about the changes I have added to the package
manager. The now empty repository, can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CarbsLinux/outsource&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New Tarball&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I have released a new tarball today, which can be obtained from the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.carbslinux.org/releases&quot;&gt;downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning to add more of these update posts as I&amp;rsquo;m feeling better about
the website structure overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Cem&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Switching to New Website</title>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cem Keylan</dc:creator>
<link>https://carbslinux.org/blog/20200128.html</link>
<description>&lt;h2&gt;Switching to New Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Jan 28 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it before, this website
was powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://werc.cat-v.org&quot;&gt;werc&lt;/a&gt;. And
even though I liked it really much, it was too
powerful for a small website like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have decided to reimplement this website with
my own static generation scripts. The source will
probably be on &lt;a href=&quot;https://carbslinux.org/git/website/log.html&quot;&gt;https://carbslinux.org/git/website/log.html&lt;/a&gt;
when I decide to publish the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The generation requires Plan9 programs, although
I have used them just for my enthusiasm. I have built
the site with a combination of mk (instead of make), rc,
and POSIX sh. I am not yet exactly familiar with rc,
but I will replace the shell scripts when I feel like
I can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
